welcome back to another video editing
欢迎回到另一个视频编辑
tutorial using the free software
使用免费软件的教程
kdenlive in this video we're going to be
Kdenlive在这段视频中我们将成为
blurring out or obscuring a certain part
模糊或模糊某一部分
of a video if we're worried about
如果我们担心的是
privacy you're protecting someone's
你在保护某人的隐私
identity or some things identity so to
同一性或某些事物同一性以便
get started I'm gonna drag in a video
开始吧 我要放一段视频
actually let's download okay I'm going
实际上 让我们下载吧 好的 我要走了
to my downloads folder and I'm gonna
到我的下载文件夹 我要
bring in this video of a Mercedes
带上这段梅赛德斯的录像带
driving so this is a good example
开车 所以这是一个很好的例子
because I'm gonna left click and drag it
因为我要左键点击并拖拽它
down into my video project actually no I
我的视频项目实际上不是我
could do that but look if I do this we
可以这样做 但如果我这样做 我们
see this Clips about 30 seconds long so
请看这段大约30秒长的视频
I could shrink it down a couple ways I
我可以用几种方式把它缩小
can left-click here and just shrink it
可以左键单击此处并将其缩小
down to the time I want so it's really
直到我想要的时间 所以这真的是
short or I can hit ctrl Z we learned we
或者我可以按下Ctrl Z键我们学到了
can grab the razor tool and we can cut
可以抓起剃须刀 我们就可以切开
this video to the length we want and
这段视频的长度是我们想要的
then just delete the other portion by
然后 只需删除另一部分即可
hitting the Delete key while it's
在按Delete键的同时
selected or I can control Z ctrl Z and
选定或我可以控制Z、Ctrl、Z和
just delete this whole thing another way
用另一种方式删除这整件事
I want to show you that you can bring
我想让你知道你可以带着
Clips in is by going to your clip
进入剪辑是通过转到您的剪辑
monitor and hitting play and then we can
监控和点击播放 然后我们就可以
use these things if you hover over it
如果你将鼠标悬停在上面 就可以使用这些东西
says set zone in and set zone out so
表示将区域设置为in 将区域设置为out
what we can do where this playhead is if
如果这个播放头在哪里 我们能做什么
I hit set zone in it creates a blue line
我击中了设定的区域 它创造了一条蓝线
if I do zone out it creates a blue line
如果我真的划出区域 它会创建一条蓝线
there and now we have we've selected a
现在我们有了我们选择了一位
zone here and if I left click and drag
区域在此处 如果我左键单击并拖动
this part of the clip it'll bring in
剪辑的这一部分将被带入
just that portion whereas if I grab this
就这一部分 但如果我拿到这个
whole thing up here it brings in this
所有的东西都在这上面带来了这个
whole long video so just this portion
整个视频很长 所以只有这一部分
now is just the portion that we did so
现在正是我们所做的那部分
it's just a certain portion it's
只是一定的一部分而已
wherever we press the the it is in and
无论我们在哪里按下按钮 它就在哪里
out of when we were watching the clip so
当我们在看这段视频的时候
what I'm gonna do I'm gonna go back here
我要做的是我要回到这里
to the clip monitor we're gonna go back
对于剪辑监视器 我们要回到
to the very beginning I'm gonna play and
从一开始我就会弹奏
this time I want in fact what I want to
这一次我想要的其实是我想要的
do I want to go to the very beginning
我想从头开始吗？
and set the end point at the very
并将终点设置在非常
beginning and I want to click forward
开始 我想点击前进
here a little bit till this until it
在这里稍微等一下 直到它
changes to the next scene and I want to
下一个场景的变化 我想
have that be the out point so right here
难道那就是这里的起点吗？
this would be the out point then I'll
这将是出场点 然后我将
drag the video in on my video track 1
将视频拖入我的视频轨道1
and I'll just zoom in
我只要放大就行了
on the timeline so we can see it better
这样我们就能更清楚地看到它
so it's just going to be a very quick
所以这将是一个非常快速的
little video clip of a car driving
一段汽车驾驶的小视频剪辑
forward what I want to do let's obscure
转发我想要做的 让我们遮掩
this license plate maybe so it says C
这个车牌上可能写着C
Class right now but maybe it actually
类 但也许它实际上
really says the license plate number and
真的写着车牌号和
we want to show this video but we don't
我们想播放这段视频 但我们不想
want to so I want to give away the
想要 所以我想赠送
privacy of like whoo you know I'm gonna
隐私 就像你知道我会
keep keep private who owns this vehicle
对谁拥有这辆车保密
and what their license plate number is
以及他们的车牌号是多少？
so to do that we need to apply mmm
所以要做到这一点 我们需要应用MMM
where's this thing even at it's under
这东西在哪里 甚至在它下面
distort no we want to do a what's it
扭曲 不 我们想要做什么？
called I kind of think of this guys I
打电话给我 我有点想这个人
said it in the introduction I said what
我在引言中说了我说了什么
it was obscure yeah so we want to go
很隐晦 是的 所以我们想去
obscure oh it's under blurring hide okay
模糊的 哦 它在模糊的隐藏下 好的
so under blurring hide we bring that
所以在模糊的隐藏下 我们带来了
drop down and we have a couple different
下来 我们有几个不同的
things we can do we can apply blur if we
我们可以做的事情我们可以应用模糊如果我们
do blur just blurs the whole thing so we
做模糊只是模糊了整个事情 所以我们
can just blur like the whole video yeah
能像整段视频一样模糊吗是的
that would work they wouldn't be able to
这将会奏效 但他们不能
read the license plate but then now so
读一读车牌 但现在是这样
we wanted we could do box blur I think
我们想我们可以做盒子模糊 我想
box blur gives us a box
盒子模糊给了我们一个盒子
oh no box blur is just a different type
哦 不 框模糊只是另一种类型
of blur nevermind what we want to
模糊的 不管我们想要什么
actually do is go down to obscure and
实际上所做的就是堕落到默默无闻
left-click and drag that in so that
左键单击并将其拖入 以便
creates a box that it obscures just the
创建一个框 它只遮挡
area where that is apt so we can move it
适合的区域 这样我们就可以移动它
around to just that license plate and we
就在那个车牌附近 我们
can actually resize it although this is
可以实际调整它的大小 尽管这是
a video so it's moving and just because
一段视频 所以它很动人 只是因为
we're setting it over the license plate
我们正在把它放在车牌上
it's not gonna be tracked to it so what
它不会被追踪到那又怎样
I mean is if the video if later on the
我的意思是 如果这段视频后来
car moves its location like it's doing
汽车移动它的位置就像它正在做的那样
so you know we can see the size of the
所以你知道我们可以看到
license plate but we can't really read
车牌 但我们真的看不懂
it so we could just go to that we can go
这样我们就可以去我们可以去的地方
forward and see what that looks like so
向前看 看看它是什么样子的
it looks pretty good there but by the
那里看起来很好 但到了
time it gets here it looks like it's
当它到达这里时 它看起来像是
covering up the emblem a little bit so
把会徽遮住一点 这样
we can just go back here and we can move
我们可以回到这里然后我们就可以搬家了
it down a little bit like this maybe and
它可能会像这样降一点 然后
maybe make it bigger just we'll put it
也许我们会把它做得更大
into a place where it's not looking to
到了一个它并不期待的地方
where it's kind of a happy medium where
在那里它是一种快乐的媒介
it's still gonna blur out the license
它仍然会模糊驾照
plate but not going to cut into that
盘子 但不会切成那样
emblem too much yeah that's probably
徽章太多了 是的 可能是
good so let's watch and see what this
很好 让我们来看看这是什么
looks like
看起来像是
play awesome so it's driving and that's
玩得很棒 所以它在开车 这就是
that box is just there it'd be cooler if
那个盒子就在那里 如果它能更酷
it was tracking to it maybe I'll make a
它正在追踪它 也许我会做一个
tell you the truth I haven't learned how
说实话 我还没学会怎么做
to do that in kdenlive yet so I'm
在Kdenlive做这件事 所以我
actually I think I did it several years
事实上 我想我已经做了好几年了
ago but I'll try and make a video
但我会试着拍一段视频
showing how to because we can track this
演示如何操作 因为我们可以跟踪它
so that it moves along with a certain
所以它会随着某个特定的方向移动
portion of the video but yeah that's
视频的一部分 但是的 那是
basically it how to obscure if we want
基本上是如何掩盖我们想要的
to obscure out something else like this
为了掩盖其他类似的事情
like there's a person standing over here
就像有个人站在这里
we can resize this we can change right
我们可以调整大小 我们可以改变方向
now the width and the height they're
现在它们的宽度和高度
locked if we click here we can unlock
锁定如果我们点击这里 我们就可以解锁
and have just the width be so we can
只要宽度适中 我们就可以
create this so this box is more like a
创建此框 使其更像是
person shape and then we can change the
人的形状 然后我们可以改变
location of it to by just coming to the
它的位置只需来到
scroll wheel and scrolling over if we
滚轮和滚动 如果我们
didn't want to move it around that way
我不想把它搬来搬去
and then yeah and then size 2 we can
然后是的然后是2号的我们可以
change the size that way as well yeah
把尺寸也改成这样耶
thanks for watching this video it's just
感谢收看这段视频 只是
a quick one that's how you obscure
一个快速的 这就是你如何掩盖的
pretty simple in kdenlive and go ahead
在kdenlive中非常简单 然后继续前进
and like comment subscribe ask me ask
喜欢评论订阅问我问
some about some videos below if there's
关于下面的一些视频 如果有
a certain type of video you want me to
你想让我
make go ahead and suggest that below and
让我们继续前进 并建议下面
I can see if I can make something like
我可以看看我能不能做一些
that thanks for watching
感谢收看